Guide to the James Olinkiewicz Collection of Photographs and Ephemera 1850s-1910, 1932 PR 404
New-York Historical Society
James Olinkiewicz collection of photographs and ephemera
1850s-1910, 1932
New-York Historical Society
Olinkiewicz, James
PR 404
3.8 Linear feet in 6 boxes.
673 stereograph cards of New York City (i.e., Manhattan) landmarks (1850s-circa 1900); one box of photographs and ephemera documenting the activities of the Kit Kat Club, an association of New York City-based artists (1888-1908, 1932); and a scrapbook of theater and recital programs, tickets, and photographs of Boston and some New York productions attended by one Mary E. Thayer (1904-1908, 1910).
Arrangement
This collection is organized in three series:
Series I.
Stereographs of New York City and Elsewhere, 1850s-circa 1900
Series II.
Kit Kat Club Photographs and Ephemera, 1888-1908, 1932
Series III.
Mary E. Thayer Scrapbook, 1904-1908, 1910
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Olinkiewicz, 2018 (accession no. PPAC-2018-037).
Related Materials
A number of the stereographs in the Olinkiewicz Collection are duplicated in the New-York Historical Society's extensive Stereograph File, PR-65, which contains upwards of 17,000 views.
Mr. Olinkiewicz has also donated to the New-York Historical Society a complete set of Brooklyn Daily Eagle postcards (PR 355), and a photographic art album for the Steamship Idlewild (PR 2, vol. 478).
Scope and Contents
This collection combines three unrelated parts received together from the same donor:
673 stereograph cards with mid- to late-19th century views of New York City (i.e., Manhattan) landmarks such as the Brooklyn Bridge, Trinity Church, Central Park, Broadway, and the Tombs prison. Brooklyn and Staten Island are represented by a few cards, as are various locations throughout New York State, Pennsylvania, and Vermont.
Photographs, bylaws, printed programs, and invitations documenting the activities of the Kit Kat Club, a New York City-based association of artists organized in 1881 and incorporated in 1884. The club counted among its members such notables as lithographer Napoleon Sarony (1821-1896) and Impressionist painter William Merritt Chase (1841-1916). The Kit Kats sponsored annual summer sketching and painting excursions, three of which are represented by photographs and ephemera here: a week-long trip by barge on the Delaware and Hudson Canal (1895); a camping trip to Pelham Bay on Long Island Sound (1896); and a sail by schooner to Stony Brook, Long Island (1897). This material was assembled by William C. Ostrander, onetime president of the Kit Kat Club, and includes some items from the Salmagundi Club and the Black and White Club, other arts organizations which counted Ostrander as a member.
A scrapbook of programs, playbills, ticket stubs, and photographs from theatrical productions and musical recitals attended by one Mary E. Thayer, mostly in Boston with a few in New York, between October 1904 and September 1908. Thayer notes in the margin who attended each performance, e.g. "Norma & I," "Bert, Blanche & I," etc.
Artists -- New York (State) -- New York; Theater -- United States.; Ephemera.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Stereographs.; New York (N.Y.) -- Photographs.; Kit Kat Club (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I. Stereographs of New York City and Elsewhere, 1850s-circa 1900
  Scope and Contents
  673 stereograph cards with mid- to late-19th century views of New York City (i.e., Manhattan) landmarks such as the Brooklyn Bridge, Trinity Church, Central Park, Broadway, and the Tombs prison. Brooklyn and Staten Island are represented by a few cards, as are various locations throughout New York State, Pennsylvania, and Vermont.
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized in four sub-series, each of which is arranged by image topic:
  Sub-series I.A.
  New York City—Bridges, Harbor, Shipping, Rivers
  Sub-series I.B.
  New York City—Manhattan
  Sub-series I.C.
  New York City—Brooklyn & Staten Island
  Sub-series I.D.
  New York State, Pennsylvania, Vermont
  - Sub-series I.A. New York City—Bridges, Harbor, Shipping, Rivers
    - NYC—Bridges—Broadway [1 card], [circa 1866-1867] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - NYC—Bridges—Brooklyn—Construction [20 cards], [1869-1883] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - NYC—Bridges—Brooklyn—General [16 cards], [1883-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - NYC—Bridges—Brooklyn—Scenes on [7 cards], [1883-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - NYC—Bridges—Brooklyn—Views from [5 cards], [1883-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - NYC—Bridges—Harlem River crossings [2 cards], [circa 1900?] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - NYC—Bridges—High Bridge [11 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - NYC—Bridges—Washington [2 cards], [1888-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - NYC—Harbor—Battery & Castle Garden (Castle Clinton) [11 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
    - NYC—Harbor—Castle Williams [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
    - NYC—Harbor—Ferries [13 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    - NYC—Harbor—Piers & docks [5 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
    - NYC—Harbor—Shipping scenes [16 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
    - NYC—Harbor—Ships—Foreign [6 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
    - NYC—Harbor—Ships—Sailing [10 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - NYC—Harbor—Ships—Steam [27 cards in 2 folders], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - NYC—Rivers—East River [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - NYC—Rivers—Harlem River & Ship Canal [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 19)
    - NYC—Rivers—Hudson (North) River [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 20)
  - Sub-series I.B. New York City—Manhattan
    - Manhattan—Alms House Commissioners Office [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 21)
    - Manhattan—Apartment houses—Dakota [1 card], [1884-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 22)
    - Manhattan—Banks [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 23)
      Bank for Saving (Bleecker near Broadway); German Savings Bank (14th Street corner Fourth Avenue); Park Bank Building.
    - Manhattan—Bible House [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 24)
    - Manhattan—Churches & Synagogues—Asbury Methodist Episcopal Church [1 card], [1850s-1895] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 25)
    - Manhattan—Churches & Synagogues—Church of the Covenant [1 card], [1865-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 26)
    - Manhattan—Churches & Synagogues—Church of the Holy Trinity [1 card], [1850s-1873] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 27)
    - Manhattan—Churches & Synagogues—Congregation Emanu-El [3 cards], [1868-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 28)
    - Manhattan—Churches & Synagogues—Grace Church [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 29)
    - Manhattan—Churches & Synagogues—St. George's Church [2 cards], [1865-1889] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 30)
    - Manhattan—Churches & Synagogues—St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 31)
    - Manhattan—Churches & Synagogues—Trinity Church [8 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 32)
    - Manhattan—Churches & Synagogues—Unidentified [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 33)
    - Manhattan—City Hall [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 34)
    - Manhattan—Clinton Hall (a.k.a. Astor Opera House) [2 cards], [1850s-1890] (Offsite-box 1, Folder 35)
    - Manhattan—Commodities exchanges [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
      Corn Exchange; Produce Exchange.
    - Manhattan—Courthouses [3 cards], [circa 1862-1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
      Jefferson Market Courthouse; Tweed Courthouse.
    - Manhattan—Department stores—A. T. Stewart [8 cards], [1862-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
    - Manhattan—Drug stores—Hembold's [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
    - Manhattan—Ethnic groups [2 cards], 1900 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
      Hebrew Quarter; Italian Quarter.
    - Manhattan—Field Building / Washington Building [2 cards], [circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
    - Manhattan—Five Points House of Industry [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
    - Manhattan—Hall of Records [8 cards], [1850s-circa 1873] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - Manhattan—Hospitals [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
      Bellevue Hospital; Lenox Hospital.
    - Manhattan—Hotels [19 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
      Albermarle House; Astor House; Harry Bertholf's Hotel on Harlem Lane; Hotel Brunswick; Fifth Avenue Hotel; Grand Hotel; Grand Central Hotel (later Broadway Central Hotel); Lafarge House; St. Nicholas Hotel; Windsor Hotel.
    - Manhattan—Markets [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
      Fulton Market; Manhattan Market.
    - Manhattan—Masonic Temple [2 cards], [1875-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - Manhattan—Metropolitan Sanitary Fair [1 card], 1864 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - Manhattan—Museums—Barnum's [1 card], 1868 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - Manhattan—Newspaper buildings [14 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 15)
      Evening Post; Herald (Park Row and Herald Square); Staats Zeitung; Tribune; World.
    - Manhattan—Panoramic views [22 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
    - Manhattan—Parades—General [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
    - Manhattan—Parades—Naval [3 cards], 1898 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 18)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Bowling Green [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 19)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Bryant Park (Reservoir Square) [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 20)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Arbors [2 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Arsenal [4 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 22)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Bridges [10 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 23)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Cave & Ice Spring [4 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 24)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Events & sports [3 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 25)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Fountains [3 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 26)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Goat Carts [1 card], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Horses [1 card], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Ice Skating [2 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 29)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Lake / Pond [7 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 30)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Mall [3 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 31)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Menagerie [1 card], [1864-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 32)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Mt. St. Vincent [1 card], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 33)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Obelisk [2 cards], 188-1896 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Ramble [2 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Roads [2 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Statuary [2 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 37)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Structures [2 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 38)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Central Park—Swings [2 cards], [1857-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 2, Folder 39)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Chatham Square [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—City Hall Park [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Madison Square [1 card], 1900 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Printing House Square [5 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
    - Manhattan—Parks & Squares—Union Square [10 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5)
    - Manhattan—Post Office (City Hall Park) [11 cards], [circa 1880-1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6)
    - Manhattan—Railroads—Depots—General [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
      Harlem River Railroad; unidentified.
    - Manhattan—Railroads—Depots—Grand Central (1871) [7 cards], [1871-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 8)
    - Manhattan—Railroads—Elevated [30 cards in 2 folders], [circa 1870s-1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - Manhattan—Residences—A. T. Stewart [3 cards], [1869-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 11)
    - Manhattan—Residences—Vanderbilt Mansion [2 cards], [1882-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 12)
    - Manhattan—Residences—Interiors [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 13)
    - Manhattan—Restaurants—Delmonico's [1 card], [1862-1876] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 14)
    - Manhattan—Schools & colleges—Cooper Institute / Cooper Union [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - Manhattan—Schools & colleges—Free Academy [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - Manhattan—Schools & colleges—National Academy of Design [4 cards], [1865-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
    - Manhattan—Schools & colleges—New York University [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
    - Manhattan—Stock Exchange [2 cards], [circa 1865-1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
    - Manhattan—Street life [10 cards], [circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
      "Peddling ties on the Bowery"; "A New York Street Organ"; "Scene in New York"; "Scene in N.Y. Slums"; "Boot Blacks"; "Try Your Weight."
    - Manhattan—Streets—14th [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 21)
    - Manhattan—Streets—55th [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 22)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Battery Place [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 23)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Bowery [9 cards], [circa 1870s-1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 24)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Pine [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 25)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Fulton [7 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 26)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Murray [5 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 27)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Chambers [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 28)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Pearl [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 29)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Canal [5 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 30)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Grand [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 31)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Broome [8 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 32)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Prince [5 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 33)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Houston [5 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 34)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ 8th Street [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 35)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ Union Square [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 36)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ 23rd Street & Fifth Avenue [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 37)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway @ 33rd Street [1 card], [1870s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 38)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway—"on a rainy day" [6 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 39)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway—"burst of sunlight after a shower" [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 3, Folder 40)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Broadway—General [28 cards in 3 folders], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Five Points [6 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
    - Manhattan—Streets—New Bowery & Roosevelt [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Park Place [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 6)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Park Row [6 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 7)
    - Manhattan—Streets—South [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 8)
    - Manhattan—Streets—Wall [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9)
    - Manhattan—Streets—West [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 10)
    - Manhattan—Streets, Avenues—Fifth [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 11)
    - Manhattan—Tammany Hall / Tammany Hotel [5 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 12)
    - Manhattan—Theaters—Academy of Music [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 13)
    - Manhattan—Theaters—Bryant's Opera House [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 14)
    - Manhattan—Theaters—Central Park Garden [2 cards], [1868-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 15)
    - Manhattan—Theaters—Gilmore's Garden (Madison Square Garden) [1 card], [circa 1876] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 16)
    - Manhattan—Theaters—Niblo's [3 cards], [1850s-1895] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 17)
    - Manhattan—Theaters—Olympic [1 card], [1850s-1881] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 18)
    - Manhattan—Theaters—Wallack's [3 cards], [circa 1861-1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 19)
    - Manhattan—Tombs (prison), old [12 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sub-series I.C. New York City—Brooklyn & Staten Island
    - Brooklyn—Brooklyn Navy Yard [3 cards], [1860s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 21)
    - Brooklyn—Churches [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1880] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 22)
      Elm Place Congregational Church; Plymouth Church.
    - Brooklyn—Coney Island [10 cards], [1870s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 23)
    - Brooklyn—Green-Wood Cemetery [7 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 24)
    - Brooklyn—Prospect Park [5 cards], [circa 1867-1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 25)
    - Staten Island—Quarantine [2 cards], before 1858 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 26)
    - Staten Island—Stapleton [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 27)
  - Sub-series I.D. New York State, Pennsylvania, Vermont
    - New York—Albany (?) [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 28)
    - New York—Chenango Bridge [2 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 29)
    - New York—Cold Spring [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 30)
    - New York—Garrison [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 31)
    - New York—Kenwood [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 32)
    - New York—Lake George [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 33)
    - New York—Oswego [1 card], [circa 1873-1881] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 34)
    - New York—Poughkeepsie [1 card], [circa 1861-1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 35)
    - New York—Pulaski [3 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 36)
    - New York—Rochester [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 37)
    - New York—Saratoga / Saratoga Springs [4 cards], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 38)
    - New York—Tarrytown [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 39)
    - New York—West Point [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 40)
    - Pennsylvania—Starrucca Creek [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 41)
    - Vermont—St. Johnsbury [1 card], [1850s-circa 1900] (Offsite-box 4, Folder 42)
- Series II. Kit Kat Club Photographs and Ephemera, 1888-1908, 1932
  Photographs, bylaws, printed programs, and invitations documenting the activities of the Kit Kat Club, a New York City-based association of artists organized in 1881 and incorporated in 1884. The club counted among its members such notables as lithographer Napoleon Sarony (1821-1896) and Impressionist painter William Merritt Chase (1841-1916). The Kit Kats sponsored annual summer sketching and painting excursions, three of which are represented by photographs and ephemera here: a week-long trip by barge on the Delaware and Hudson Canal (1895); a camping trip to Pelham Bay Park in the Bronx (1896); and a sail by schooner to Stony Brook, Long Island (1897). This material was assembled by William C. Ostrander, onetime president of the Kit Kat Club, and includes some items from the Salmagundi Club and the Black and White Club, other arts organizations which counted Ostrander as a member.
  The material in Series II was originally pasted or laid in a scrapbook, but had been removed and possibly reordered before it came to the New-York Historical Society. The archivist has left the photographs in the order in which they arrived, but has grouped the loose ephemera chronologically.
  - Kit Kat Club. Collection description, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
  - Kit Kat Club. Photographs [5 folders], circa 1895-1897 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2-6)
  - Kit Kat Club. Newspaper clippings, 1895-1897 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
  - Kit Kat Club. Ephemera [13 folders], 1888-1908, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 8-20)
  - Salmagundi Club. Ephemera, 1897-1898 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 21)
  - Black and White Club. Ephemera, 1900, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 22)
  - Nan Kee letter to William C. Ostrander & family, 1932 April-May (Offsite-box 5, Folder 23)
- Series III. Mary E. Thayer Scrapbook, 1904-1908, 1910
  Scrapbook of programs, playbills, ticket stubs, and photographs from theatrical productions and musical recitals attended by one Mary E. Thayer, mostly in Boston with a few in New York, between October 1904 and November 1908. Thayer notes in the margin who attended each performance, e.g. "Norma & I," "Bert, Blanche & I," etc.
  The scrapbook runs chronologically, from October 1904 through November 1908, then skips to April 1910, where it ends.
  - Mary E. Thayer Scrapbook, 1904-1908, 1910 (Offsite-box 6)